

Profile

As a web developer, I have designed, developed and provided support for several web applications. Experienced with different JavaScript frameworks especially React. Knowledgeable in debugging processes. Equipped with a diverse and promising soft skill-set. Competent in an array of technologies, including NodeJS, MongoDB, and Continuous integration approach. Easily collaborate in a team setting.

Education

MSc of Geospatial Technologies (Erasmus+ category A scholarship holder), [Universitat Jaume I (UJI), Castellón, Spain] and [Münster University, Münster, Germany]

September 2017 — March 2019

Universitat Jaume I (UJI), Spain: Web-programming focusing on full-stack application development using AngularJS and NodeJS.

Münster University, Germany: Study about data manipulation using python and incorporating it in the web platform. Master thesis title "Querying Spatial datasets with ease through an Application Programming Interface (API)." Full-stack application for the thesis study developed with JavaScript.

Bachelor of Science in Environment Management, School of Environmental Science and Management, Kathmandu, Nepal

November 2011 — October 2015

Github repository for Master thesis study

Spatial Datasets retrieval API developed for Master thesis, Münster university, Germany

September 2018 — February 2019

API endpoint: https://giveourdata.herokuapp.com/api/

• Github repo: https://github.com/angsherpa232/Retrieve_dataset

Internships

Junior Frontend Developer at geOps, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany June 2019 — September 2019

- Develop a Jest based test-driven library (tree-lib) for the Single page progressive web App (tree-app).
- Develop reusable React components based on graphic/web designer design.
- · Incorporate spatial functionality.
- Write end-to-end testing based on cypress for the entire app.

1. live-app: https://tree-app.ch

tree-app: https://github.com/geops/tree-app
tree-lib: https://github.com/geops/tree-lib

Details

Zähringer Str. 28, Freiburg im Breisgau, 79108, Germany, +49-177 862 4852 angsherpa232@gmail.com

Links

Github Linkedin

Skills

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

React

Node.js

Scss

Git/Github

MongoDB

Python

ArcGIS (Desktop, Arcpy library)

QGIS

PostgreSQL

Web-mapping

Languages

English

German

Nepali

Hindi

National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) DEVELOP program. at ICIMOD, Kathmandu

June 2015 — August 2015

- Worked with Landslide Identification Product together with Hazard Assessment Model for detecting Landslides. Detail can be obtained through the link below.

https://develop.larc.nasa.gov/2015/summer_term/HimalayaDisastersII.html

Employment History

Web Team at Erasmus mundus - Geomundus conference, Münster, Germany

June 2018 — December 2018

- Worked on a web team to design, code, test, report, and debug operations.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems.
- Made changes to specific pages based on Google Analytics statistics and updating the website periodically.
- Website link: http://geomundus.org/2018/

ELIPPSS: Web-portal for drone images at "Unmanned Aerial System" Course Project, Münster, Germany

April 2018 — September 2018

- Developed and hosted a web-portal in the scope of the Unmanned Aerial Systems course at the Institute of Geoinformatics.
- Github repo: https://github.com/angsherpa232/UAS_web2018

Geographic Information System (GIS) technician at Department of Irrigation, Kathmandu, Nepal

February 2015 — August 2017

- Assisted sub-consultancies for web-mapping based on libraries such as Leaflet. Effectively worked on requirements into mapping applications.
- Developed ArcGIS tools based on python script and ArcGIS ModelBuilder.

Courses

React the complete guide (hooks, Redux), Udemy 2019

Complete React full stack course, Udemy 2018

Google Earth Engine based on Javascript, International Centre for Integrated Mountain Development (ICIMOD)

May 2017 — May 2017

■ References

References available upon request